Contact

3535 E Calle Del Prado (520) 975-0159 (Mobile) peraltawave@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mperalta (LinkedIn) peraltawave.github.io/ resume-2019/ (Personal)

Top Skills

Corporate Identity
Television Production
Web Design

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual) Spanish (Native or Bilingual)

Miguel Peralta

Freelance front-end designer and React developer Tucson, Arizona

Summary

I am an enthusiastic and experienced creative team leader and graphic designer. I have recently earned a post grad certificate in full stack web development program at the University of Arizona to complement my nearly 20 years of visual design experience.

Specialties: Web Design, Content Management, Branding, Web Site Design and implementation.

Recent studies focused on MERN stack front-end development: MongoDB, Express, React and Node.

Front-end: JavaScript, JQuery, Material UI, Bootstrap, React.

Projects and samples: https://peraltawave.github.io/resume-2019

Experience

Peraltawave Studios Design and Development Consultant September 2017 - Present

Tucson, Arizona Area

Currently working as a freelance graphic designer and web development consultant to over twenty clients, providing branding, web and print design as well as web hosting.

PrestoSports, Inc.
Creative Director
September 2007 - August 2017 (10 years)
Washington D.C. Metro Area

PrestoSports gathers in-game data from over 900 universities and colleges around the country. Their need was creative management and the development of a consistent approach to layout and design so that varied statistical data follows branding guidelines from clients across multiple

Page 1 of 3

platforms. As Creative Director, I created and managed designs from multiple designers for nearly 700 clients. In addition I created and executed a full rebranding of the corporate logo, marketing materials and website.

Highlights

Full corporate re-brand
Managed 6 designers
Launched over 700 sites
Established style guide
Mobile and Responsive Design

NextWest, Inc Design & Marketing 2004 - 2007 (4 years)

Tucson, Arizona

NextWest provided voice-over-IP services and technology with it's own telephony solutions. I was design lead on the re-branding of the flagship product line which included on-line and print marketing materials, manuals and physical decal applications.

Winning Communications
Art Director
January 2001 - December 2003 (3 years)
Dubai. UAE

Winning Communications is a publishing house based in Dubai, UAE. With circulation of over 150k readers, their two print magazines, The International Indian and The Middle East Review remain popular in the Middle East. As Creative Director, I managed the design and print from concept to delivery. Worked closely with the production manager and designers to ensure design quality and consistency.

CNET Networks
Art Director
January 1999 - December 2001 (3 years)
Miami, Florida

CNET established a Latin American office in Miami to serve South and Central America with their award winning content in both Spanish and Portuguese.

As Art Director, I was tasked with producing and editing various graphic deliverables in both languages for four different content channels.

Yahoo Senior Graphic Designer May 1997 - December 1998 (1 year 8 months) Greater Los Angeles Area

Yahoo! Music acquired Launch Media, based in Santa Monica, CA which delivered the very first internet music streaming service: LaunchCast. I was lead on the interface design for LaunchCast, including design, usability, graphic naming conventions and multi-skin design and testing

Education

University of Arizona
Certificate, Full Stack Web Development · (2018 - 2019)

Loyola Marymount University BA, Communications · (1992 - 1996)